<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 11:59:18 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 11:59:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Ignite International Girls Hackathon, My First Hackathon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was asked to volunteer at this event, I remember thinking, REALLY? I just started learning to code, what in the world can I possibly contribute to this. But, in spite of the fear and doubts, I reluctantly agreed. For me, coding was taking me leaps out of my comfort zone, and I knew this was going to be no different. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day of the hackathon, I was so nervous. Nervous about showing my lack of knowledge, looking like an imposter, not being beneficial to the event. But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing I learned that day- this was not about me. This was about a group of girls who wanted to spend a weekend coding and solving problems larger then themselves. Yes, they asked questions that I was not ready to answer, but like I had already been doing in class, we looked it up, solved it and moved on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did not let my fear get the best of me. For more information about Ignite or how the day went, check out the post I wrote for 
&lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.generalassemb.ly/coding-for-change-opportunity-fund-fellow-mentors-all-girl-hackathon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;General Assembly&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/post5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/post5/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>assembly,</category>
        
        <category>nyc,</category>
        
        <category>opportunity</category>
        
        <category>fund,</category>
        
        <category>coding,</category>
        
        <category>bootcamp,</category>
        
        <category>mentoring,</category>
        
        <category>girls</category>
        
        <category>who</category>
        
        <category>code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ignite International Girls Hackathon, Mi Primer Hackathon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cuando me preguntaron si queria ser uno de los voluntarios en este evento, recuerdo que pensé, de veras? Apenas empeze a aprender código, que posiblemente puedo contribuir. Pero, a pesar del miedo y mis dudas, aceptó, pero un poco de mala gana. Para mí, codificación me ha llevaba saltos fuera de mi zona de comodidad, y sabía que esto no seria diferente. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El día del hackathon, estaba tan nerviosa. Nerviosa de mostrar mi falta de conocimiento, siendo vista como una impostora, y no ser beneficioso al evento. Pero está la cosa que aprendí- esto no se trataba de mí. Se trataba de un grupo de chicas que querían pasar un fin de semana codificacando para resolver problemas más grandes de ellas mismas. Sí, tuvieron preguntas que no sabia como responder, pero como ya había estado haciendo en clase, buscamos las respuestas en linia, resolvimos las preguntas y siguimos adelante.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En retrospeca, me alegro que no dejé mi miedo obtener lo mejor de mí. Para obtener más información acerca de Ignite o cómo fue el día, visita la entrada que escribí para el &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.generalassemb.ly/coding-for-change-opportunity-fund-fellow-mentors-all-girl-hackathon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blog de General Assembly blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/entrada5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/entrada5/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>assembly,</category>
        
        <category>nyc,</category>
        
        <category>opportunity</category>
        
        <category>fund,</category>
        
        <category>coding,</category>
        
        <category>bootcamp,</category>
        
        <category>mentoring,</category>
        
        <category>girls</category>
        
        <category>who</category>
        
        <category>code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;m a General Assembly Code for Change Scholarship Recipient!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It started with a tweet. This tweet, from &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://women2.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Women 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt; to be exact:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/scholarshipTweet.png&quot; alt=&quot;scholarship tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, let me back up. Before that tweet, I had spent a few months learning HTML and CSS. Through &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Team Treehouse&amp;rsquo;s online tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;, blog posts and John Duckett&amp;rsquo;s &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.htmlandcssbook.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HTML&amp;amp;CSS design and build websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt; book, I created a website. It was not fancy, but it was functional. Not going to downplay this, it was a pretty great feeling to see the working links, a responsive header (everything else was responsive too, but the header was where I could see the most transition) and something I created on my computer&amp;rsquo;s screen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the weeks past, I was reading and going through more complicated frontend tutorials and dipped my toes into backend as often as I could. But, something was missing. Structure. I applaud those who have been able to learn on their own, without classes, bootcamps, etc. There are a lot of resources out there, but I knew that if I wanted to continue on this path, I would have to commit full-time. I thought about going back to school, but then I saw the tweet about scholarships for women looking to learn to code. On that list, was &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://generalassemb.ly/opportunity-fund&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;General Assembly&amp;rsquo;s Opportunity Fund&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;. Since I received the scholarship, the format has changed a bit, and now all scholarships fall under two categories, Web Development Immersive and User Experience Design Immersive. But at the time, I specifically received the Alexis Ohanian Fellowship for Women of Color. Scroll down to Fellows Spotlight for some info on some of the scholarship recipients, including me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty scared to apply, for many reasons. For starters, if I did get a scholarship, that would mean quitting my job, while my husband was in school full-time. Also, I can work my way through problems, but I was no math or science whiz, so I was concerned that coding was out of my leauge. Honestly, I could keep going with the list of why nots, bu I got over the fears and applied anyway. I thought, what are the odds&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I few weeks later, I was called in for an interview, with both the Opportunity Fund Director and a teacher at General Assembly. Needless to say, I was pretty intimiated, but later that evening I was informed that I would be given the scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months since I finished the program and had the privilage of teaching a Girls Who Code class in Harlem soon after I was done. I&amp;rsquo;ve been coding just about everyday since graduating, but I had planned to travel throughout the summer while my husband, Josh, finished school and an internsip, so I have postponed looking for a full-time job. Late last week, we Josh officially accepted a data science/web development job in Durham, NC. So were packing up and heading south! It&amp;rsquo;s been a crazy few months, but I am so very excited to get involved with the thriving tech community in the Raleigh/Durham/Chapel Hill area of North Carolina. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/post4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/post4/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>assembly,</category>
        
        <category>nyc,</category>
        
        <category>opportunity</category>
        
        <category>fund,</category>
        
        <category>coding,</category>
        
        <category>bootcamp</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Oportunidad Becaria para atender General Assembly</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Todo comenzó con un tweet. Este tweet, para ser exacto de &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://women2.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Women 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt; para ser exacto:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/scholarshipTweet.png&quot; alt=&quot;scholarship tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bueno, antes de ese tweet, había pasado algunos meses aprendiendo HTML y CSS. A través de tutoriales de diseño de web en el sitio &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Team Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;, entradas de blog y el libro &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.htmlandcssbook.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HTMLyCSS diseño y construcción de sitios web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt; escrito por John Duckett, construi my primer sitio web. No era algo lujoso, pero fue una gran sensación ver los vínculos trabajando, navegacion responsivo (todo el sitio era responsivo, pero la transición fue más evidente en la navegacion) y en general, algo que yo crei con codificación que pudo ver en mi computadora. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Segui leyendo y aprendiendo, usando tutoriales mas complicados de frontend y empeze a aprender un poco del backend, pero algo faltaba, estructura. Aplaudo a las personas que han sido capaces de aprender diseño de web por su cuenta, sin clases, bootcamps, etc. Se que hay un montón de recursos, pero yo quería estar en clases y aprender de ellos que saben mas que yo. Pensé volver a la escuela, pero luego vi el tweet acerca de becas para las mujeres que desean aprender código. En esa lista, aprendi de &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://generalassemb.ly/opportunity-fund&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Opportunity Fund de General Assembly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;. Desde que recibí la beca, el formato ha cambiado un poco, ahora todas las becas estan bajo dos categorías. Yo específicamente recibi la beca Alexis Ohanian Becas para Mujeres de Color. Visita la pagina para mas informacion acerca de los becarios, incluyendo mi!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tenia muchas reservaciones pensando en la posibilidad de aprender codificación. Para empezar, la beca significaría dejar mi trabajo, mientras mi marido estaba en la escuela tiempo completo. Ademas, puedo trabajar mi camino a través de problemas, pero no soy un genio de matemáticas o las ciencias, así que estaba preocupado de que la codificación estaba pueda ser mas dificil para mi. Honestamente, podría seguir con la lista de por qué no, pero aplique. Pensé, ¿cuáles son las probabilidades &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unas semanas más tarde, me llamaron para una entrevista, con el Director de Opportunity Fund y un profesor de General Assembly. No hace falta decir que estaba bastante intimidada, pero esa misma noche me informaron de que gane la beca.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ha sido un par de meses desde que termine el programa y tuve el privilegio de enseñar con Girls Who Code en Harlem, NY. He estado codificación casi todos los días desde que gradue del progrema, pero había planeado viajar durante el verano, mientras que mi marido, Josh, termina sus estudios y un internado, así que he pospuesto buscar trabajo de tiempo completo. La semana pasada, Josh oficialmente aceptó una posición de ciencia de datos/diseño de web en Durham, Carolina del Norte. Así que nos vamos sur! Han sido unos locos meses, pero estoy muy emocionados de ser parte de una comunidad próspera tecnología en el área de Raleigh/Durham/Chapel Hill en Carolina del Norte .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/entrada4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/entrada4/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>assembly,</category>
        
        <category>nyc,</category>
        
        <category>opportunity</category>
        
        <category>fund,</category>
        
        <category>coding,</category>
        
        <category>bootcamp</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ruby-build&amp;#58; definition not found&amp;#58; 2.2.3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve used &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sstephenson/rbenv&quot;&gt;rbenv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt; to update my Ruby dependencies in the past, usually without a problem. But, while trying to update to the Ruby&amp;rsquo;s 2.2.3 version, I ran across this error: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$rbenv&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;definition&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;found&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;The&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;following&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;versions&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;contain&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sb&quot;&gt;`2.2.3&amp;#39; in the name:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;sb&quot;&gt;rbx-2.2.3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After double checking that the current stable version is in fact &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/downloads/&quot;&gt;2.2.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;, I looked into ways to update manually. The solution to this is in the ruby-build, a rbenv plugin that provides an install command to compile and install different versions of Ruby on UNIX-like systems. Additionally, I use a package manager, &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brew.sh/&quot;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;, and the following commands worked for me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$brew&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Downloading&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;https&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sstephenson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v20150928&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gz&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Downloading&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;https&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;codeload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sstephenson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v20150928&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;######################################################################## 100.0%&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;/install&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sh&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;🍺&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/usr/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;local&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Cellar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;20150928&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;172&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;728&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;K&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;built&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seconds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then entered the following, which gave me a warning: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$brew&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;link&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;Warning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Already&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;linked&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/usr/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;local&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Cellar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;20150928&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;To&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;relink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;brew&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;unlink&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;brew&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;link&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I tried to update through git, which worked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$cd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;~&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/.rbenv/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;plugins&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;  
&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$git&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pull&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$rbenv&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;global&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$ruby&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p173&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;08&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;revision&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;51636&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x86_64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;darwin14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m now up and running on the current stable version. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/post3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/post3/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ruby,</category>
        
        <category>rbenv,</category>
        
        <category>homebrew,</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ruby-build&amp;#58; definición no encontrada&amp;#58; 2.2.3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;En el pasado, he usado &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sstephenson/rbenv&quot;&gt;rbenv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt; para actualizar mis dependencias, generalmente sin ningún problema. Pero, al intentar de actualizar a la versión de Ruby 2.2.3 , me encontré con este error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$rbenv&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;definition&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;found&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;no&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;encuentra&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;definition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;The&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;following&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;versions&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;contain&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sb&quot;&gt;`2.2.3&amp;#39; in the name: (Las versiones que contienen &amp;#39;2.2.3&amp;#39; en el nombre:)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;sb&quot;&gt;rbx-2.2.3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Después de comprobar que la versión estable es, de hecho, &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/downloads/&quot;&gt; 2.2.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;, busque formas de actualizar la versión manualmente. La solución a esto esta en Ruby-Build (osea la construcción), un plugin rbenv que proporciona un comando para compilar e instalar diferentes versiones de Ruby en sistemas tipo UNIX. Además de usar rbenv, tambien uso un gestor de paquetes, &amp;lt; html&amp;gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brew.sh/&quot;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;, y los siguientes comandos trabajaron para mí.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$brew&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Downloading&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;https&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sstephenson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v20150928&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gz&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Downloading&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;https&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;codeload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sstephenson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v20150928&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;######################################################################## 100.0%&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;/install&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sh&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;🍺&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/usr/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;local&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Cellar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;20150928&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;172&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;728&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;K&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;built&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;seconds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luego entré en la siguiente, que me dio una advertencia :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$brew&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;link&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;Warning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Already&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;linked&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/usr/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;local&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Cellar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;20150928&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;Advertencia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;¡&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Ya&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;vinculada&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/usr/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;local&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Cellar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;20150928&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;To&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;relink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;brew&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;unlink&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;brew&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;link&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Para&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;volver&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;vincular&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;desconectar&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;brebaje&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;enlace&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;brebaje&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Así que traté de actualizar la construccion a través de git, la cual trabajó:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$cd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;~&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/.rbenv/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;plugins&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;  
&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$git&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pull&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$rbenv&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;global&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;vg&quot;&gt;$ruby&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ruby&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p173&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;08&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;revision&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;51636&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x86_64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;darwin14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahora estoy trabajando con la version actual. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/entrada3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/entrada3/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ruby,</category>
        
        <category>rbenv,</category>
        
        <category>homebrew,</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lista De Contactos Con localStorage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://contactlist12.herokuapp.com/&quot; class=&quot;project_link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ver En Línea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
|
&lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/IvetteAddington/Contact-List&quot; class=&quot;project_link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View Source Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Acerca de Este Proyecto&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuando estuve en classes en General Assembly, nuestro segundo proyecto era crear una lista de contactos. En ese momento, recuerdo que la lista de entregablesme dejo un poca abrumada. Complete casí todo lo que estaba en esa lista, pero supe que revisitaria este proyecto en el futuro. Así que esto es Lista de Contactos 2.0 con algunos cambios un poco de cambios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para empezar, los requisitos del proyecto incuia direciones de crear una base de datos usando PostgreSQL para guargar toda la informacion acerca de nuestos contactos. No tengo nada en contra de postgres, por lo general, es lo que uso para mis proyectos. Pero, queria usar localStorage, que permite acceder al objeto local Storage sin fecha de expiración usando pares de llaves/valors. Eso es una breve explicación de localStorage, pero si deseas leer un poco mas acerca del tema, &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintohtml5.info/storage.html&quot; target =&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dive Into HTML5&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt; tiene un capitulo dedicado a localStorage. Además, la versión original mostró todos los contactos o separados por categorías (omití las categorías en esta versión), pero la función para búsquar en esta version devuelve todos los contactos que contienen las entradas en el nombre. Finalments, jugué con algunas funciones de jQuery animación jQuery y toggle para mostrar la información final.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Desafíos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lo que me llevó más tiempo fue la animacion dejQuery . A menudo, cuando una función empezo a trabajar, otra se rompería. Además, originalmente pense que mostrando la información de contactos en una tabla de HTML, pero eso me dio pocas opciones  para mostrar la información de la manera la qual había planeado. También me encontré con momentos en los que el código hice lo que quería que hiciera dentro localStorge, pero no cambiaría la información en el DOM sin ​​una actualización de página. Así que tenía que asegurarme de que lo que estaba ocurriendo en localStorafe se reflejaria en el DOM. Pero, creo que mi mayor desafío era atravesar el DOM. He trabajado con el DOM en el pasado, así que estaba un poco frustrado que no pude podia codigar la animación deseada para los elementos padres e hijos. Pero después de un descanso y leer más cuidadiosamente en el tema, finalmente tenia las functionces trabajando. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Pensamientos Finales&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Todavía puedo ver las cosas que me gustaría editar, pero todavia no estoy segura cómo&amp;hellip; por ejemplo todo el espacio blanco en la párte derecha , la edición del CSS para los enlaces de paginación, cosas que probablemente revisitare  versión 3, pero por ahora estoy feliz de haber aprendido a trabajar con el localStorage, la animación jQuery trabajado de la manera que intente. Me tomó un poco más de tiempo de lo que esperaba para con estos cambios, pero realmente esta mucho mejor de la primera versión. Importantements, puedo ver mi crecimiento personal, que en el fondo era el propósito de volver a visitar este proyecto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Recursos Usado&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;html&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jquery.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jquery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Window/localStorage&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Local Storage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://t4t5.github.io/sweetalert/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sweet Alert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.listjs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;list.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://st3ph.github.io/jquery.easyPaginate/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;easyPaginate.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://getbootstrap.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/proyecto3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/proyecto3/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Contact List w/ Local Storage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://contactlist12.herokuapp.com/&quot; class=&quot;project_link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
|
&lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/IvetteAddington/Contact-List&quot; class=&quot;project_link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View Source Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;About this Project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was at General Assembly, our second project was to create a contact list. At the time, I remember being overwhelmed by the MVP list. Although I delivered most of what was on that list, I remember thinking I would come back later and redo it. So this is Contact List 2.0 and there was quite a bit of changes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For starters, the original project had us create a postgreSQL database for for the contact&amp;rsquo;s information. I have nothing against postgres, its my go-to for databases. But, over the past few weeks, I had wanted to work on a small project that incorporated local storage, a way for web pages to locally store name/key value pairs. That is the simply put definition, but for a more in depth look at local storage, check out &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintohtml5.info/storage.html&quot; target =&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dive Into HTML5&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt; chapter dedicated to local storage. Also, the original version either showed all the contacts or would break them up into categories(I omitted the categories on this version), but the search feature on this returns all contacts that contain the inputs in the name. Lastly, I played with some jquery animation and toggle functions to display the information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What took me the longest was getting the jquery right. Oftentimes, once I got one feature working, something else would break. Also, I had originally set up the contact information to save in a table format, but the gave me limited options when it came to displaying the info the way I had planned. I also came across times where the code did what I wanted it to do within local storge, but would not change the info on the DOM without a page refresh. So, I had to make sure that what was happening in local storage was being reflected on the DOM. However, I think my biggest challenge DOM traversal. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with the DOM in the past, so I was a bit frustrated that I could not get the animation to work on the child elements at first, but after a break and some more careful reading on the subject I was able to get the functions working. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can still see things here and there that I would like to edit, but not sure how to yet&amp;hellip; for example all the white space on the search portion of the page, editing the css for the pagination links, and I&amp;rsquo;ll likely get to those in version 3, but for now I&amp;rsquo;m happy to have learned how to work with local storage, as well as getting jquery animation working the way I intented it to. It took a little longer than I hoped to get these edits done, but it truly is so much better that the first version, and I can see my personal growth, which deep down was the purpose of revisiting this project. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Resources Used&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;html&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jquery.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jquery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Window/localStorage&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Local Storage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://t4t5.github.io/sweetalert/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sweet Alert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.listjs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;list.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://st3ph.github.io/jquery.easyPaginate/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;easyPaginate.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://getbootstrap.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/project3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/project3/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dynamic Navigation with Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started to plan the functionality of this blog, I wanted the site&amp;rsquo;s navigation to change according the the user&amp;rsquo;s choice of language, while giving the option to easily switch back and forth from one language to another. To accomplish this, I created a custom navigation file in a Jekyll &lt;html&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/datafiles/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; data folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/html&gt; (_data). Within Jekyll, a data file can be used to store additional, non-out-of-the-box functionality to customize a site. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, I wanted two seperate navigations that would alter according to the language (page.lang) the user was currently on. So, to start I created navigation.yml inside of _data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;├──&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_data&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;│  &lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;└──&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;navigation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;yml&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In navigation.yml I created two sets of navigations- one in English (en) and one in Spanish (es). The &amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo; is what will appear on the navbar, with its corresponding &amp;ldquo;url&amp;rdquo; below it. One thing to keep in mind here- YAML, like Python, is pretty specific about its whitespace, so make sure to use the spacebar instead of tab for spacing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;en&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Posts&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;/index/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;projects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Projects&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;/projects/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;about&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;About&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;/about/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;es&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;entradas&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Entradas&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;/entradas/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;proyectos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Proyectos&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;/proyectos/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;acerca&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Acerca De&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;21&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;/acerca-de/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To complete the navigation functionality, in default.html I looped through navigation.yml according to the current [page.lang]. This code allows the user to navigate through the rest of the site in that same language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ul&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;nav navbar-nav pull-right&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;navigation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;lang&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;    &amp;lt;li class=&amp;quot;list-inline&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;     &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;{{ menu[1].url }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{ menu[1].title }}&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;    {% endfor %}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted the ability to transition from one language to another in the navbar, but only wanted the counterpart language link to show. So, if the user was on an English post, only see the &amp;ldquo;Español&amp;rdquo; link and the opposite for a Spanish post. I chose that for two reasons. First, I did not want the navbar to look crowded with unnecessary links and second, there is no need to link to the page/post the user is already on.        &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, on lines 1 and 2, I had to create the variable to be able to loop through the posts. The &amp;lsquo;where:&amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; filter traverses through the posts to look for its post/page counterpart. I then had to &amp;ldquo;capture&amp;rdquo; the language of the page. Line 4 depicts the capture tag- which is a block tag that captures text into a variable to then use that variable to determine the result of the following if/else statement. As that variable goes through the if/else statement, that determines which languge link to display- English or Español. Once the languge is determined, I used a liquid filter, line 7, to replace &amp;ldquo;en&amp;rdquo; (the variable used to differentiate between the two languages) with the word &amp;ldquo;English&amp;rdquo; and remove the &amp;ldquo;es&amp;rdquo; (for Español), since the user is already reading in a Spanish language page. And vice versa on line 11, when the user is on an English page. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;assign&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;sort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;path&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;%} &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;    {% for post in posts %}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;li&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;lang&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;capture&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;language&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;%}{{page.lang}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;endcapture&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;%} &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;        {% if language == &amp;quot;es&amp;quot; %}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;{{ post.url }}&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;{{ post.lang }}&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;              &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;lang&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;post.lang&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;replace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;English&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;remove&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;es&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/a&amp;gt; &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;        {% else %}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;{{ post.url }}&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;{{ post.lang }}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;                {{ post.lang | where: &amp;quot;post.lang&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;es&amp;quot; | replace: &amp;quot;es&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Español&amp;quot; | remove: &amp;quot;en&amp;quot; }}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;            &amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;endif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;    &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;    {% endfor %}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;16&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
   

&lt;p&gt;I then used the same format on the templates for projects and posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/post2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/post2/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll,</category>
        
        <category>navigation,</category>
        
        <category>bilingual</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog Dedicado a Comida</title>
        <description></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/proyecto2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/proyecto2/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
